https://youtu.be/VvgNbmuvWWU
anlynguyenphuoc_gtc_Y2VjYm 07/09/2016
Apache Spark is based on research
Apache Spark dựa trên cơ sở nghiên cứu
that was done here in the Amp Lab
ở phòng thí nghiệm Amp
at the University of California, Berkeley.
thuộc Đại học California - Berkeley.
If you'd like to learn more about the history of Spark,
Nếu bạn muốn tìm hiểu về lịch sử Spark,
you can read some of the research papers.
hãy đọc một số tài liệu nghiên cứu.
This is the first publication about Spark,
Đây là ấn bản đầu tiên về Spark,
and it appeared in June 2010 at a workshop.
phát hành vào tháng sáu, 2010 tại một buổi hội thảo.
It's a short paper, at six pages,
Nó là một tài liệu ngắn, dài 6 trang,
and provides an interesting insight
cho thấy một góc nhìn sâu sắc
into the start of Spark.
về khởi đầu của Spark.
This paper, "Resilient Distributed Data Sets:
Bài viết "Resilient Distributed Data Sets:
A Fault-Tolerant Abstraction for In-Memory Cluster Computing"
A Fault-Tolerant Abstraction for In-Memory Cluster Computing"
is the first conference paper about Spark,
là báo cáo hội nghị đầu tiên về Spark,
and it appeared in April 2012.
phát hành vào tháng tư năm 2012.
This paper is an invited paper titled
Bài viết này là bài viết mở đầu,
"Spark SQL: Relational Data Processing in Spark"
tựa đề "Spark SQL: Relational Data Processing in Spark"
that appeared in June 2015.
phát hành vào tháng sáu năm 2015.